Guide to the Consumer Reports. Washington Office records, 1966-1997 and undated RL.11775
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports. Washington Office records
1966-1997 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports (Firm)
RL.11775
2.0 Linear Feet
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. The Washington Office opened in 1972 focused on representation of consumer interests before government institutions. Collection includes correspondence, status reports, position papers, statements and testimonies before Congressional committees and other government agencies, and other printed materials. Topics addressed include energy policy, food marketing and safety, product safety and other subjects relating to consumer protection. Institutions represented include the Center for Law and Social Policy, Consumer Product Safety Commission, and the U.S. Food and Drug Administration. Originally designated Record Group 1LD in Consumers Union Archives. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General Files; Center for Law and Social Policy.
Biographical / Historical
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. The Washington Office opened in 1972 focused on representation of consumer interests before government institutions.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Consumer Reports. Washington Office records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2019.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Cause Marketing Forum. Halo Awards records
J. Walter Thompson Company. Marketing vertical files
J. Walter Thompson Company. Information Center vertical files
McCann-Erickson Worldwide vertical files
Collection Overview
Collection includes correspondence, status reports, position papers, statements and testimonies before Congressional committees and other government agencies, and other printed materials. Topics addressed include energy policy, food marketing and safety, product safety and other subjects relating to consumer protection. Institutions represented include the Center for Law and Social Policy, Consumer Product Safety Commission, and the U.S. Food and Drug Administration. Originally designated Record Group 1LD in Consumers Union Archives. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
consumer protection; Energy policy; Product safety; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
- General Files, 1966-1997 and undated; 1
  - 25th anniversary booklet, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Consumer Product Safety Commission, 1977, 1981; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Consumer Product Safety Commission--Lawn mower safety standard, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Consumer publications, 1970-1975 (Box 1)
  - Consumer representation plan, 1976-1979 (Box 1)
  - David Swankin--Statements, testimonies, petitions, 1968-1972 (Box 1)
  - Energy Conservation Coalition, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Energy policy project, 1974 (Box 1)
  - European consumer programs, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Food and Drug Administration--Diethylstilbestrol suit, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Issues Update newsletter, 1990 (Box 1)
  - James Brodsky--Statements and testimonies, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Joel Joseph, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Mark Silbergeld--Statements and testimonies, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Mark Silbergeld--Statements and testimonies, 1973-1977 (Box 3)
  - Memos and correspondence, 1968-1979; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Minnesota Pollution Control Agency, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - Oil import economic analysis, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Oil import fee, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Peter Schuck--Articles, notes, 1972-1975; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Peter Schuck--Statements before Congress, 1973-1977 (Box 3)
  - Postal regulations, 1974-1977 (Box 2)
  - Power mower safety standard, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Product, warranty complaints and reports, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Recommendations concerning Washington Office, undated (Box 2)
  - Sharon Nelson--Statement to Senate Subcommittee, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Southland mower safety petition, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Status reports, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Status reports, 1974-1977 (Box 3)
  - Steel imports suit, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Virginia State Board of Pharmacy et al v. Virginia Citizens Consumer Council, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Washington Post article on flammable sleepwear, 1972 (Box 2)
  - White House Health Professionals Review Group, 1993 (Box 2)
- Center for Law and Social Policy, 1972-1980; 2
  Biographical / Historical
  Established in 1968 to advocate for interests of low-income, women and other underrepresented people and communities. In the 1980s it narrowed its scope of activities to focus on poverty issues.
  - Auditor's report, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1980; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Credi card lawsuit proposal, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Energy Transportation Security Act, 1977 (Box 2)
  - International Project funding, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1972-1975 (Box 3)